In this lecture, we're going to focus on AWS Lambda.
So if you look at the architecture for AWS,
it's a completely serverless service.
In the case of EC2 instance,
we had seen some of these layers were managed by AWS
and few of them were managed by the customer.
But in case of the AWS Lambda,
so if you see the physical layer,
you have the host OS, hypervisor, execution environment,
sandbox execution, Lambda runtime,
everything is managed by AWS.
And as a customer, the only thing you need is the Genia code,
which you can either write in Python, Java,
and supports most of the programming languages.
So that's in terms of the architecture.
If you look at the management, it's a fully managed AWS service.
So AWS manages everything, including infrastructure,
scaling, maintenance, you don't need to worry about anything.
Now in terms of the pricing model for AWS Lambda,
it's pay as you use.
So every time you create a Lambda function,
you have to allocate some memory,
and then you'll be charged based on the memory allocated.
The execution time, let's say your Lambda function,
runs the Genia code and logic for five minutes.
So you'll be charged for that five minute execution time.
And number Lambda invocation.
Now in terms of the execution limit,
so this is important.
Lambda has a maximum 15 minute execution time per invocation.
If the execution time limit is more than 15 minutes,
then you need to either take a look at ECS or EC2.
Okay, in terms of the scaling,
it's automatic and dynamic based on the request volume.
So typically for each account in a region, it's about 1000,
but it can be increased to tens and thousands if you send a request to AWS.
Okay, now the important thing, the use cases.
So the first one is you can write the orchestration logic for your Genia.
Now let's try and understand this through an example.
So this is the most common architectural pattern for AWS Genia applications.
So you have the API gateway, Lambda, and Amazon bedrock.
So the key things to remember about AWS Lambda,
it's an event driven serverless compute service.
So what event driven means that it's not going to run by itself.
Unless there's a trigger, there's an event.
It will not run and you'll not be charged for it.
Okay, so what's an event?
Let's say our user sends a prompt,
summarize the winter by logs.
So that's an event.
Okay, so once he sends that request through the API gateway,
it will go to AWS Lambda function.
And here you can write your prompt orchestration logic.
So maybe you'll use some prompt engineering techniques.
Maybe you'd send the information related to the model,
inference parameters, system prompts, and so on.
And then it will be sent to Amazon bedrock,
and then you'll get a response.
So that's the first use case.
The second one is on a rag apps.
So AWS has a managed service called as bedrock knowledge bases,
and we're going to deep dive into that.
It's another important exam topic in the next section.
So bedrock knowledge bases provides two APIs,
retrieve and retrieve and generate API.
So you can write the book of three code in your Lambda function
to retrieve the data from a rag-based apps,
especially bedrock knowledge bases.
Okay, so we already discussed that it can be used to write
orchestration logic for journey apps.
Then it can be used for racks, retrieve and retrieve and generate API.
And then it can also be used as a tool for Amazon bedrock agents.
And we're going to discuss that in the section three,
but just remember it can also be used for Amazon bedrock agents.
Now let's take a look at couple of scenarios where you cannot use AWS Lambda.
So first you cannot do foundation model hosting on AWS Lambda.
Second, you cannot use it for long running tasks.
Now the task execution is more than 50 minutes,
then you cannot use AWS Lambda.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.